- Can I tell you something I'm bad at?
我想跟你分享一件我不擅长的事
I am terrible at making clickbait.
我非常不擅长当“标题党”
Up until two years ago,
在两年前那会
my most popular video was about
我最火的视频是讲的是
a basketball being dropped from a dam with a bit of backspin.
把回旋的篮球从水坝上扔下来
It takes off like a rocket
篮球像火箭一样飞出
and shoots out way further than you'd expect.
飞得比你想象的远得多
This video was embedded
这个视频被嵌入到几百个新闻网站中
on literally hundreds of news websites.
And in its first week, it got 16.3 million views,
在视频发出一个星期内获得了 1630 万次浏览
but almost none of those views came on the YouTube platform.
但来自 YouTube 平台本身的浏览量却寥寥无几
Why?
为什么？
Because I gave it this thumbnail
因为这是我给它的封面
and I called it "Strange Applications of the Magnus Effect."
并将其取名为「马格努斯效应的奇怪应用」
This video is sponsored by KiwiCo.
More about them at the end of the show.
Now, I believe within YouTube,
我相信，我现在在 YouTube 被认作
I'm used as an example of how not to package your video.
不去“包装”自己视频的典型例子
As if to demonstrate just how bad a title and thumbnail this is,
就像是为了凸显原来的标题和封面有多烂
someone else re-uploaded the video with the clever title,
有人重投了这一视频  换了个聪明的标题
「从水坝上扔下的篮球」
And within a few weeks,
短短几星期内
that video had received tens of millions of views on YouTube.
这个视频就在 YouTube 上获得了几千万浏览
This is when YouTube gave me access to ContentID.
这时候 YouTube 给了我 ContentID 的使用权限
That's the system that allows you to earn revenue
这个系统在别人转载你的视频时  能让你从中赚取收益
when someone else re-uploads your videos,
which was good, but I still wasn't very good at clickbait.
这很不错  但我还是不擅长当标题党
So for this video, I called in an expert.
所以本期视频  我请了一位专家
I wanted to see your reaction face.
我想看看你的震惊脸
Can you give me like a reaction face?
能否让我看看你的震惊脸？
Like what's a good thumbnail face?
有什么表情适合放封面上？
- Oh, I got you.
哦  我懂
This is a thumbnail face.
这是一个用作封面的表情
I have like 10, I go through the motions of like...
我有十个这样的表情  就比如像这样
And then we just take the best one,
然后我们选择最好的一个
I probably have like 500 of these just saved
我大概存了五百个像那样的表情
and we can just Photoshop my face on my face.
然后我们直接 PS 这些表情
That way, I don't have to do it anymore.
这样我就不用再做表情了
- When I started on this platform, some 10 years ago,
大约十年前，当我刚加入这个平台时
clickbait was less important.
标题和封面没那么重要
Subscribers were what mattered,
重要的是关注者
because most of the views came from the sub feed.
因为大部分的点击  都来自向关注者的推送
And videos went viral usually by getting a lot of attention elsewhere,
视频爆红一般是靠其他地方的流量
like on Reddit or Facebook,
比如 Reddit 和 Facebook
not due to the YouTube algorithm.
而不是靠 YouTube 的算法
But once you had a big video and people subscribed,
但一旦你有个视频火了  吸引人们关注
well, then your next video would likely get a lot of views from those subscribers.
那你的下一个视频  很可能就会从关注者那里得到很多浏览
So YouTube would take that popular video and share it with more people.
于是 YouTube 就把热门的视频  分享给更多人
And so you'd get more subscribers
这样你会获得更多的关注者
in a positive feedback loop.
形成一个正反馈循环
But soon, YouTube realized that
但 YouTube 很快意识到  这给观众的体验并不太好
this did not create the best experience for the viewer.
They discovered that showing people only videos
它们发现  光给人们展示他们订阅频道的视频
from channels they were subscribed to
led to fewer clicks, less watch time and less engagement
会导致网站的点击数、观看时间、互动量均整体下降
with the site as a whole.
Plus, they knew that relying on other platforms
况且他们知道  靠其他平台引流创造爆红视频  有风险
to drive traffic to viral hits was risky,
since those other platforms might disable the traffic at any time.
因为其他平台可以随时砍掉这些流量
So they needed to make YouTube a destination in itself.
所以他们要让 YouTube 本身成为流量目的地
They wanted people to come to YouTube,
他们希望人们来到 YouTube
see videos that interested them,
看他们感兴趣的视频
click on at least one of them and watch it for a while.
点击其中至少一个视频并看一段时间
Ideally get sucked down the YouTube rabbit hole
最好掉进 YouTube 的陷阱里
and spend hours on the site without even noticing it.
不知不觉地在网站上花费数个小时
The ultimate resource is people's time and attention,
最终极的资源  还是人们的时间和注意力
and every platform is trying to capture as much of it as possible.
各大平台无不希望尽可能攫取用户的这些资源
So, to make YouTube this go-to destination,
因此，为了让 YouTube 成为这个目的地
they had decrease the importance of subscribers,
它们减少了关注者的重要性
make it less like a podcast app
让它不像播客应用那样  只能收听已订阅的节目
where you only get the shows you're subscribed to,
and more like Reddit,
而是更像 Reddit
where stuff with the most engagement rises to the top.
互动最多的东西被顶到最前面
But that necessarily meant increasing the importance of clickbait.
但那必然意味着  提高标题和封面的重要性
Now, there seems to be a paradox when it comes to clickbait.
但关于“标题党”却有一个矛盾
People almost universally claim to hate it,
“标题党”几乎人人喊打  却也随处可见
but you also see it everyhere.
So why is this?
这是为什么呢？
Well, one of the problems is we don't all agree
其中一个问题在于  我们没有明确“标题党”的定义
on the definition of clickbait.
When I google it, the top definition is,
我在谷歌搜这个词的时候  第一条定义是
on the internet, content whose main purpose
在互联网上，用于吸引注意力、鼓励访客
is to attract attention and encourage visitors
to click on a link to a particular webpage.
点击某个网页链接的内容
We could call this type I clickbait,
我们可以把它叫做「第一类标题党」
and there doesn't seem to be anything wrong with it.
而且它本身似乎没有什么错
I mean, if you didn't try to attract attention
如果你不去吸引人们的注意力  让人点击你的链接
and get people to click on your links,
then you wouldn't really be doing your job.
那等于没做你该做的事
But there is a second definition.
但它还有第二种定义
One that I think more people ascribe to,
一种我认为有更多人理解的定义
which is something such as a headline designed
一个让读者想去点击网页链接的东西  比如标题
to make readers want to click on a hyperlink,
especially when the link leads to content of dubious value or interest.
尤其是链接到内容可疑的网页时
Wikipedia says, "A defining characteristic of clickbait
维基百科说「标题党的一个根本特征是
is that it is sensationalized or misleading."
情绪化或有误导性」
And it also talks about teasers
它还提到了一种故意卖关子  来吊人胃口的标题
that intentionally withhold information to exploit the "curiosity gap."
They give you enough information to make you curious,
它给你足够多的信息  来激发你的好奇心
but not enough to satisfy that curiosity.
但不足以满足你的好奇
Here are two actual titles from a news website.
这里是某新闻网站上的两个标题
《十个美国人有九个完全搞错了 这一惊人的事实》
《某人给小孩们发了几把剪刀，接下来发生了这些》
I think we can all agree that
我觉得我们都会认可
these are examples of bad type II clickbait.
它们属于坏的「第二类标题党」
Now, imagine a clickbait space
想像把各类“标题党”放在平面内
where on one axis, you have how misleading or sensationalized it is.
横轴描述  它的误导性或者情绪化程度
And on the other, how much information is intentionally withheld
纵轴描述  它为了设置悬念而隐瞒了多少信息
to create a curiosity gap.
Well, then these two titles fall in the top right corner.
刚才这两个标题就落在右上角
And these are the zones of type II clickbait.
这些就是第二类标题党所在的区域
At the other extreme,
而在另一个极端
you have things that are so unsensationalized as to be dull.
这些标题是如此平淡  以至于有点枯燥
You could call this the dead zone.
可以把这边称作“盲区”
Now, here is where you would find
在这片区域  你可以找到
"Strange applications of the Magnus Effect."
“马格努斯效应的奇特应用”之类的标题
I mean, I didn't tell you what the applications were.
因为标题没有点明这些应用是什么
Now, in the middle is where you would find type I clickbait.
中间则是第一类标题党的所在
But honestly, I think type I and type II clickbait are so different,
但是讲真  这两类标题党有着巨大的差别
that we shouldn't even use the same word for them.
大到我觉得不应该归结为同一个词
Instead of type I clickbait,
与其叫“第一类标题党”
my friend and YouTuber, Brady Heron suggested legitbait.
我一位油管主朋友 Brady Heron 认为  不如叫「合理标题党」
I mean, it might sound enticing, but it is legit.
这种标题听起来很诱人  但是并无误导性
Instead of type II clickbait,
与其叫“第二类标题党”
we could use clicktrap, clicktrick, linktrap or dupechute.
不如改称「点击陷阱 / 点击诡计 / 陷阱链接 / 整蛊链接」
What's important to recognize is that
还要意识到一个重要的事实
for any given video, there is no one true title and thumbnail.
哪个视频都没有唯一准确的标题和封面图
Each video could have hundreds or thousands of different legitbait titles.
每个视频都可以有成百上千各不相同的“合理标题”
For example, how does a zero-G plane work?
比方说《零重力飞机是如何运转的？》
I went on a plane that does parabolic trajectories.
《我坐上了一架沿抛物线飞行的飞机》
What happens to fire on a zero-G plane?
《零重力飞机上的火焰会发生什么？》
Now, the most enticing titles and thumbnails
可以发现，最有诱惑力（但合理）的标题和封面图
are found close to type II clickbait.
非常接近第二类标题党
I'm reminded of the infographic by smarter every day,
我想起 SmarterEveryDay 制作的那张图表
showing that on social media, the greatest engagement
那张图表明  社交媒体上最有吸引力的话题
occurs close to the boundary of what's allowable.
都是在违法的边缘疯狂试探
But remember that everyone's definition of clickbait is different,
但要记住  每个人判断标题党的标准不同
and everyone's perceptions of words and images are different.
每个人对相同文字和图片的理解也不同
So these are not clear boundaries.
所以这些类别并非泾渭分明
They're actually kind of fuzzy.
它们之间的边界  事实上比较模糊
What for one person might be legitbait,
某人觉得是“合理标题党”的标题
for someone else, could be a clicktrap.
在另一个人看来  可能就是“点击陷阱”
What's clear is that on a site where click-through rate is important,
显然  在一个重视点击率的网站上
clickbait of all types is inevitable.
出现这两类标题党都是难以避免的
How important to a video's success is the title and thumbnail?
标题和封面  对一个视频的成功有多大帮助
- Very important. Of course.
当然非常重要
If they don't click on the video, they don't watch it.
如果观众不点进视频  他们压根看不到它
You can't get 10 million views
只有你获得了一千万点击
unless 10 million people click on the video.
才有可能收获一千万的播放量
So, I mean, it's literally that simple.
所以  它就是这么简单
They don't click on it, they don't watch it.
不点进去  何谈观看呢
- So, why is clickbait everywhere?
所以  为何到处都是标题党呢
Well, because it works.
因为它行之有效
More enticing thumbnails get more clicks.
封面图越吸引人  收获的点击数越多
Despite some people's claims that they won't click or they'll unsub,
尽管有人声称  自己坚决取关这些作者、不点开这类视频
it's just like evolution.
但是这机制类似于生物的演化
Whatever survives, multiplies and traits become amplified.
生存竞争中的赢家就会增殖  其特征会得到强化
If you don't begrudge the giraffe its long neck
如果你觉得长颈鹿的长脖子是它应得的
so it can reach the highest leaves,
使它能吃到顶上的树叶
can you begrudge a YouTuber the red arrow
那凭什么UP主就不能出奇招来吸引更多观众呢
that allows them to reach further audiences?
I talked about this in my video two years ago.
两年前我有期视频聊过这个
To be successful as a YouTuber, you need to optimize two things,
想当一个成功的up主  需要优化两个数据
watch time and the click-through rate of your videos.
观看时长  以及视频的点击率
That's the number of times the title and thumbnail are clicked,
即用户从视频封面点进去看的次数 / 视频的总推送次数
divided by the total number of times they're shown.
That's the number of impressions.
推送次数即为「曝光量」
Now at the time, this was something of a revelation for me
这个概念在当年让我耳目一新
because I always thought my job was to make great videos.
因为我一直觉得  我的职责就是制作优质的视频
And then a title and thumbnail that adequately represented what the video was about.
还有能恰当呈现视频主旨的标题和封面
But now I've realized that making the title and thumbnail is at least half the job.
但我现在意识到  构思标题和封面费的工夫不亚于做视频
This is not just because better titles and thumbnails get you more clicks,
这不只是因为  更好的标题和封面能带来更多点击
but because better titles and thumbnails will get you way more impressions.
还因为它们可以给你带来多得多的曝光量
YouTube has limited real estate
YouTube 得在有限的地盘里
with which to show you virtually infinite content.
给你推送几乎无穷多的内容
And so it's not enough to make a good video even if people watch all of it,
仅仅做出让观众愿意看完的好视频  是不够的
you also have to make a title and thumbnail that gets clicked,
你还得搞个能吸引人点击的标题和封面
especially in competition with other really good titles and thumbnails.
才能在一众优秀的标题和封面中  脱颖而出
That's the only way you can expect YouTube to give you more impressions.
要想在 YouTube 得到更高曝光量  你别无他法
Now, the big development since my last video on this
自从我上次做同样话题的视频后，有了一个大进展
is YouTube introduced real-time metrics
YouTube 引进了实时的度量指标
like views, impressions and click-through rate.
包括观看次数，曝光量和点击率等等
Now, I suggested this would create an arms race.
我觉得  这会带来一场创作者的军备竞赛
So what you can bet will happen is that creators will launch a video
几乎可以肯定  接下来的创作者在发布视频后
and then they'll be sitting there with all these different variants of thumbnails
就会一直鼓捣各种不同的封面
and they'll be swapping them out
再把不同封面换来换去
and looking at what that does to click-through rate
看看对点击率有什么影响
and then going with the one that leads to the greatest click-through rate.
最后敲定使用点击率最高的封面
And this is basically what has happened.
现状基本上就是这样
Let me give you my favorite example.
举个我最喜欢的例子
Last year, I made a video about asteroids,
去年底我做了一期讲小行星的视频
which I thought was really good.
这期我自己感觉不错
I called it
我给的标题是
《小行星：地球受到的最大威胁》
which is something Stephen Hawking said.
语出史蒂芬·霍金
And people were very positive about the video.
观众对这个视频的评价很积极
They thought it was maybe one of my best,
他们觉得  这有望跻身我最受欢迎的视频
but the performance was well below average.
但其播放量让人大跌眼镜
In its first day, asteroids was ranked ninth out of my previous 10 videos.
上线第一天  在我最近十部作品里  它的播放量为倒数第二
It was probably on target for about one and a half million views.
这样下去  这期视频的播放量预计在150万左右
So I tried different titles and thumbnails like
于是  我尝试了不同的标题和封面
《小行星撞击：我们有多少机会？》
《小行星撞击：我们能做什么？》
But none of these changes got much traction.
但这些改动没有什么吸引力
And then on day three after launch,
但到了第三天中午
I changed the title and thumbnail to
我把标题和封面改成了
《这些小行星撞击地球才是我们真正得担心的》
BV1TK4y1L7x9
And immediately the video started doing better.
这则视频立刻就有了起色
It quickly shot up from almost my worst performing video to my best.
它很快就从我表现最差劲的视频之一变成了最好的
It now has 14 million views.
现在它已经有1400万次观看了
Nothing about the video changed,
视频本身没有任何变化
just that one image and 38 characters.
仅仅是换了一张封面图片和一句话
But because of that, the video has reached nearly 10 times
正因如此，这个视频的人气比改之前高出了十倍
as many people as it otherwise would have.
And the title and thumbnail accurately describe what the video is about.
并且标题和封面准确地描述了视频的内容
I mean, sure, there's a curiosity gap,
当然 标题里确实是卖了个关子
but you couldn't explain the whole concept in the length of the title.
不过你没法在标题中就能完全说清楚
So if you see a YouTuber changing titles and thumbnails,
所以如果你看到一个UP主改了标题和封面
this is why.
这就是原因
Because that effort can be rewarded many times over.
因为这种做法能得到数倍的回报
I've seen people objecting to this practice
我也见到有人反对这种做法
because they think the creator is trying to dupe their audience,
因为他们认为这么做是在欺骗观众
get them to click on the same video more than once,
让他们重复点击一个视频多次
but that's not it.
但是事情并非如此
The whole point is to get YouTube to show the title and thumbnail to more people.
关键在于让视频平台向更多的人展示标题和封面
We're trying to increase the number of impressions,
我们这样做 是为了提高视频的展示次数
which is heavily dependent on the click-through rate.
而这个次数严重依赖点击率
Now, a lot of my recent videos have this typical view curve.
最近我的许多视频都有这种典型的观看曲线
There's an initial spike after I release the video
在我发布视频之初会火一下
and then a dip,
之后是一段低谷
and then a second bump after I have figured out a better title and thumbnail.
在当我想到更好的标题和封面之后，观看量又有明显上升
I change the title and thumbnail and I watch the real time view graph.
我换掉标题和封面，然后观察实时播放量统计
What I'm looking for is a noticeable bump in views.
我期望的是观看量会有明显的增加
Sometimes there's no change, sometimes it gets worse,
但是有时候并没有变好 可能还会更差
but on occasions, when you see something like this,
但有时也会看到这样的图像
well then, you know you've found a winner.
这说明你成功了
This is something all the big YouTubers are doing.
这是所有知名油管主都在做的事情
Not even Mr. Beast knows exactly which thumbnail will work best beforehand.
即使Mr. Beast也没法事先知道哪个封面是最好的
Mr. Beast：粉丝最多的美国油管主
Have you ever changed a title and thumbnail and then the video did better?
-你有没有过换完标题封面后，视频表现更好了
- Oh, of course.
-哦 当然
So everybody, I usually make like two or three thumbnails,
我一般制作两三个封面
and then if it's not doing as well as I want,
如果一上来没有达到想要的效果
we usually just swap 'em out and see if it does better.
我通常会换个标题封面看看有没有改善
'cause the thing is like, you don't really know.
因为除非你开挂了
I mean, you could know if you just were an almighty being
你不可能知道人们感兴趣什么
that could just predict what people would be interested in,
你只能猜他们会对什么感兴趣
but you know, usually...
但是 通常
Like, you can do hide and seek.
比如说 你整了个捉迷藏的视频
You don't really know if like you hiding in a tree
封面可以是 你藏在树上 树下有个人走过
and then someone walking below you is a good thumbnail.
Or if you hide in a trash can and them walking in front of you.
或者藏在垃圾箱里 他们从你前面走过
So, you know, just do both
不知道哪个好  就两者都试试
and then see which one interests people a little bit more.
看看哪个更能激起人们的兴趣
- I feel the same way,
我也这么想
but I do feel like you have a better sense of this than like most people.
但我觉得跟大部分人相比，你对此有更好的把握
- Of course.
当然
I mean, no one gets 40 million views a video.
要不然人人都一个视频4000万次播放了
- But what is the point in getting more views?
但是更多播放是为了什么呢
If you're cynical,
如果你觉得人皆利己
you might say it's all about money and fame.
你可能会说这都是为了名利
And while there are certainly financial incentives to getting more views,
而其中固然有经济上的动力
that's not why I do it.
这并不是我追求更多观看的原因
As an educational YouTuber,
作为一个教育向的UP主
I think there are two very good reasons
我认为有两个比较重要的原因
for using excellent type I clickbait over more straightforward packaging.
让我们应该用一类标题党  来代替平铺直叙的标题
To understand the first reason,
第一个原因的话
let's consider two different possible titles for my most recent video.
先来看看我上一期视频  草拟的两个不同标题
I called it "The Simplest Math Problem No One Can Solve,"
一个标题是 「这道看似简单的数学题没有人解得出来」
BV1Ty4y1778o
but it's a video about the Collatz conjecture.
但这视频是有关角谷猜想的
So perhaps a more straightforward title
所以一个更直接的标题是
would have been simply to call it that.
就直接写角谷猜想
The problem is, if I publish a video called the Collatz conjecture,
问题在于，如果我发布一则名为角谷猜想的视频
the most likely people to click on it
最可能点进来看的  是那些已经知道角谷猜想的人
are those who already know what the Collatz conjecture is.
And the vast majority of people will never have heard of it.
而大多数人从未听说过它
So for them, the title is meaningless
所以对他们而言 这个标题是无意义的
and only the very curious
只有他们中抱有相当好奇心的
or those who really like Veritasium would click.
或者真理元素的老粉才会点击
In contrast, calling it "The Simplest Math Problem No One Can Solve,"
相比之下 把它叫做 「这道看似简单的数学题没有人解得出来」
conveys more information about the video to everyone.
能给大众传达了更多有关视频的信息
And this means more people can click on it,
这意味着更多人会点进来
most of whom will never have heard of the Collatz conjecture.
尤其是更多从未听说过角谷猜想的人
So I get to teach them something new.
这样我才能教他们新知识
And since the video has a higher click-through rate,
并且由于视频有更高的点击率
YouTube shows it to even more people.
YouTube 会向更多人展示它
So if my aim is to increase the level of knowledge
所以如果我的目标是通过最大化数量
in the world by the maximum amount possible,
来提升世界人民的知识水平
this is the way to do it.
这就是我的做法
The second reason we need to optimize titles and thumbnails
另一个需要优化标题和封面的原因是
is to support the major goal of this channel.
为了支持这个频道的中心目标
We are trying to make the best science films on every topic we tackle.
我们正试着  就我们解决的每个问题  制作最好的科普影片
That means traveling to meet experts in film experiments,
这意味着去拜访摄录实验的专家
hiring people to build props,
请人制作道具
make spectacular animations, research and fact check.
制作壮观的动画效果 研究 和事实核查
We hire expert consultants
我们聘请专业顾问
to double and triple check our work.
来反复核对我们的工作
I don't wanna make vlogs.
我想拍的可不是 vlog
I wanna make science documentaries on YouTube
我想在YouTube上制作的科学纪录片
that put broadcast to shame.
足以让电视台的节目相形见绌
And to make this possible and sustainable,
并且为了让这个目标能够实现且能长期保持下去
the videos have to get views and lots of them.
我的视频就要有非常大的播放量
And to do that, we have to make the best titles and thumbnails we can.
为达此目标  我们就得想出足够好的标题和封面
YouTuber and Patreon CEO, Jack Conte
Jack Conte, Patreon 的 CEO  也是一位油管主
has talked about adjusting your packaging.
讲到了关于如何包装视频的问题
The idea is know what you're passionate about,
其主旨是  要清楚你最热衷于什么
what you won't compromise on
不会对什么妥协
and that stuff goes in the box.
把这些核心的东西装在盒子里
All the rest, like what paper it's wrapped in,
其余的那些  比如用什么样的纸来包这个盒子
that's the packaging.
这就是包装的问题了
So the video is my focus and the
类比一下  视频内容是我最专注的
title and thumbnail are the packaging that I'm happy to adjust,
而标题和封面则是视频的漂亮包装  可以随意调整
so I can make the type of videos that are important to me.
如此一来  我才能制作出我心目中地位甚高的视频
Now, is it ironic that a channel whose whole purpose
那么 如果现在有个频道
is to promote a true seeking mindset
它旨在为人们培养求真心理
has to experiment at the edge of what is truthful
但它得在真理的边缘疯狂地不计后果地试探
in order to fulfill that purpose?
来达到它的目的  这不是很讽刺吗
It is something that I often worry about.
这是我通常会担心到的问题
You know, when I did like risking my life to do X,
你知道  当我确实喜欢冒险去做一件事
it's like, well, what probability of death
那时候我就想着“行吧 得有多大可能会没命
does there have to be for you to risk your life?
才会让我冒生命危险去做这个事情呢”
Like 50%?
比如 50%？
- I love how he always overthinks things.
- 我很喜欢的是 他总会把事情想的很复杂
That's funny.
真的很好玩
He's like, is my life risked enough
他就这么想的“我是不是已经快到没命的边缘了
where I can put I risked my life?
所以才来冒生命危险呢
I only had a 9% chance of dying
我大概只有 9% 的可能会没命
and I need at least a 13% chance.
但我需要它至少是 13%”
You're so funny.
这也太好玩了
He was the same way two years ago
两年前他也是这样
when he asked me all this stuff.
问的我这些问题
I was like, "Dude, just do whatever makes the most sense.
我那时就想「得了吧哥  干点有意义的事情它不好吗」
- Yeah, I mean, obviously I feel like my instincts are not good.
确实  我觉得我的直觉并不是那么准
But what I realized is that I don't have to trust my instincts.
但我后来意识到  我并不需要相信我的直觉
This problem of getting the best title and thumbnail,
关于什么样的封面和标题可以吸引眼球
well, it's a scientific problem.
实际上 这是个比较科学的问题
We're just asking which accurate representation of the video
问题其实就是 怎样准确地描述这个视频
will get the most clicks from a general audience.
才能有更高的可能让普通大众点进来呢
And that's a problem we can use
这就是我们可以用科学方法
the scientific method to solve.
来解决的问题
So I've hired a couple of really bright people
所以我请来了几个有头脑的人
and we spend a lot of time brainstorming
一起花了很久的时间进行大脑风暴 集思广益
and making titles and thumbnails and testing them out.
想出有意思的标题和封面 并把它们用在视频上
For example, on Twitter and Patreon.
比如在 Twitter 和 Patreon 上
Varitasium titles and thumbnails have gotten better,
我们的标题和封面的点子越来越惊奇
not because I'm better at it,
不是因为我在这方面更熟练了
but because of my team and our testing.
而是归功于团队智慧和测试经验
If you have ideas about how we could do it better, please get in touch.
如果你有办法帮助我们更好地取名、选封面  请联系我们
The results have often contradicted what I expected.
不过  结果往往与我的期望恰好相反
I mean, this video seemed to perform 10% better
比如看这个视频 在我把“惊人的”这个词
when we excluded the word surprising from the title.
从标题里面拿掉之后 播放量较之前多了 10%
So it became simply
此时它就是
「同步之秘」
I thought these two titles were basically a toss up,
我原以为这两个标题就是个二选一
你不是一个视觉学习者                                      教育界最广泛的误区                |
but Patreon had a strong preference for one over the other.
但 Patreon 告诉我其中一个很受欢迎
What's interesting about this research is that
而对于这个研究 非常有趣的是
the more clickable titles and thumbnails
一个能吸引人们点击的标题和封面
often better represent the content of the video.
通常都能更好地表达  视频的主题
Let me give you some examples.
来看几个例子
One thing I didn't expect when YouTube brought in the real time analytics tools
在 YouTube 上线实时统计数据分析功能
and allowed title and thumbnail changes to affect impressions,
并允许更改视频封面和标题  来改变人们的印象的时候
was that it would also work for older videos.
我没想到老视频同样可以这么做
So here is an old video that I originally entitled,
这是我最初给一个老视频起的标题
「为什么说中子是核物理的英雄」
In hindsight, it's a weird, kinda meaningless title.
事后看来  这个标题显得很奇怪  毫无意义
So I changed it to,
所以我把标题换成了
「爱因斯坦为何认为没法造出核武器」
It's clearer, more accurate.
这个标题更清晰  更精确
And this is what happened to views after the change.
这是我改了标题之后  播放量的变化
I changed
我把
「马格努斯效应的奇怪用法」
to
改成了
「在水坝上来一个后旋投篮」
Again, more accurate.
也改得更精确了
And the video is now being watched on YouTube
然后现在这个视频在 YouTube 上的播放量
probably 10 million more views than it otherwise would have had.
比我修改标题之前涨了 1000 多万呢
Even anti-clickbait has proven effective.
事实证明非标题党类型的标题也是可以发挥作用的
Here's a video I originally titled,
这是我最初给这个视频起的名字
"Are Negative Ions Good For You?"
「负离子对人真的有好处吗」
Which is a question nobody asked ever.
这是个此前没人问过的问题
Now, I changed it to, "Do Salt Lamps Work?"
然后我改成了「离子灯对人真的有用吗」
（没用.jpg）
Seriously.
认真讲
And here's the result:
这就是它换了名字的结果
One and a half million more views.
涨了 150 多万播放量
I think looking at these examples,
我觉得 通过观察这些变化
you could easily make the case
你可以很容易得出结论
that YouTube has made me better at what I do.
YouTube 让我在制作视频这方面更上一层楼
It has improved the clarity and accuracy of my titles and thumbnails.
它使我的标题和封面更加清楚、准确
It's helped me figure out what is interesting to my audience
还让我摸清了  观众对什么内容感兴趣
and how to encapsulate that in a single image and fewer than 50 characters.
以及如何将内容浓缩为一张图和 50 字母内的标题
For those of you who worry that a focus on titles and thumbnails
有观众会担心  我重视标题和封面
will prevent me from picking challenging science topics,
可能会让我选一些  不那么有挑战性的科学话题
well, I simply ask you to look at the videos
我觉得，我还是要请你们去看看我们
from the last year or two,
近一两年发布的视频
like the ones on Gödel's incompleteness theorem,
比如那个讲哥德尔不完备定理的视频
general relativity, Penrose tilings,
还有广义相对论  彭罗斯密铺
the logistic map, Newton's method of calculating Pi,
单峰映射  还有牛顿的逼近圆周率的方法
the one way speed of light.
和测量单程光速的视频
Good titles and thumbnails make it possible to tackle these topics
好的标题封面可以紧扣主题
and to reach more people who have heard of them before.
能让视频被推送给更多的听过此话题的观众
There is a symbiotic relationship
视频的播放量和视频内容的质量之间
between views and video quality.
有着紧密的相互依存的联系
The more views we get, the more people,
因此，有了更多的播放量，我们才能付出更多的人力
locations, props and equipment
使用更多更好的场地 道具和设备
and research we can invest in.
并进行更缜密的研究
This makes the next video better than the last.
这才能让下一期视频的质量比之前任何一期都要好
If we can be good at titles and thumbnails,
那么如果我们可以掌握想出好的标题封面的方法
the ultimate outcome is better videos.
那么最终一定就能做出更好的视频
That is something I think you and I both want.
我认为这就是你我共同追求的目标